good everyone, i hope you guys have an  amazing day
so today i will be  starting a new salesforce certification  series
that is the CPQ specialist
CPQ is a very popular
certification on salesforce space
it's a  specialized certification
that's one of  the reason why you can see the name "CPQ specialist"
now the the word CPQ means
Configure
Price
Quote
now you must be wondering, okay so that's cool,
that that sounds familiar
but what  the heck is CPQ anyways right
so in simple terms, you can, you can  say CPQ is a tool
for companies to provide accurate pricing
with any given product configuration scenario
so  that's in a nutshell, so i'll be talking in details as we go along with the certification
so today  what i'm going to do i wanted to talk
about the exam guide and and the topics which we're going to cover right
so this is just an intoduction round
so  but i i still believe that it's very important
because i wanted to give you information around the total passing score
and different things around the  certification
right, so, the first thing i wanted to  mention to you guys
i would highly encourage you to take  this certification
only after you have some experience with CPQ
the reason why i'm saying right, CPQ is a specialized certification, right
and, or i would say
if your company demands you to have a CPQ certification because a project is coming
projects in pipeline
and so for instance, your company put a tender out
and they're expecting some CPQ work
yeah then i would highly
encourage you to go for the  certification
but, if you are someone planning to take the certification just for the sake of it
i would tell you guys to hold on for some time right
it's good to  have some real life experience with the CPQ
because you know
if you don't have a CPQ experience then it it don't make  much sense
i do have CPQ experience that's the reason why
i'm going to teach you guys about this certification
i'm  not an i'm not a 100..  like a super  super expert
but i have real life practical experience working with CPQ
right now,  who can take this certification? right
so i would say pretty much anyone right
but in saying that, this certification is more applicable for functional consultants
solution architects
even if you  are  a technical architect you know it's not  a bad certification to have
that being said right if you are someone who are going to focus mostly on the CPQ side of things
for that person CPQ certification, you know it's going to be very important
okay now let's look at the exam guide right
so, the best way to look at the exam  guide, you just go to the trailhead
and  you'll get all the information, it's  pretty simple right?
so when you look at the exam guide
right, so this is a spring 2022 release
so, this is what they expect
you know talk about  the things which they're going to expect
so before we dive into the exam outline right
let me
show you something
so what normally salesforce expects
of you know, before you go and take the certification
they expect you  to have
some knowledge on CPQ right
what that  means is that they expect you to know
how to configure bundles
how to  configure code line pricing fields
and  how to configure a dynamic code template
using code terms
how to utilize the ordering and contracting process
and you should know how to manage
products price books and price book entries
you should have a little bit or quite
a decent understanding
about native and advanced rules
you should know how to configure search
custom actions for product selections configuration
knowledge about CPQ object data model
now if you're thinking that what i'm  saying
sounds like a jargon to you
it's all right don't worry about it right
i'm gonna cover everything from the start
so but in saying so right
i still believe right
if you have a little
bit of real life experience with CPQ
it  will  be good for you guys right
if you don't, that's fine
all right so
they will not test you anything about
apex or visual force page or billing
or CPQ plug in's so
you know you don't have to worry about it
so i mean salesforce certifications are pretty flexible
the main intention for them to test you
is to know whether you  guys can do the job right
obviously the purpose of certification is
to get to yourself upskilled right
that's the way i look at it
so it will  give you an opportunity
to learn new things, give you an opportunity to
you know do something different which
you haven't done before
which is  fantastic in my personal opinion
because i always love to do something new
and also it's an opportunity to showcase
to your future employers
that hey, uh i got the certification
so i'm pretty confident that i can do the job
around CPQ right, so
okay so kind of the job roles right
so like i've already mentioned that you  know if you're a technical architect function
architect or consultant, implementation consultants
that's most commonly used terminology
for the job titles
who, you know for for the people who
are going to take the  certification
because most of the  companies will have consultants right
in  consulting space you have, often you have functional consultants and technic consultants
so they are  often called as the functional  implementation consultant or technical  implementation consultant
so, i mean the term term varies from  companies to companies right, so
just remember this right, you know all of this profiles
you can see, you can see right, so it's applicable to them
okay  now let's look at the real meat of the  certification right
number of questions, obviously 60 multiple choice questions
so the format is pretty much the same like every
other certifications you have taken in salesforce space
the passing score is 65%  which is  not too bad
registration fee is 200 usd so, if you fail the certification
you can retake by paying hundred dollars right on the usd
fantastic right
now um you can take online certification
or you can, online in the center, you can take it from home or
you can take uh you know from a testing center
so that's about the, you know housekeeping stuff when it comes to certification
so, let's look at the exam outline right
so, in this like the expected to know CPQ platform
which is like, which is 23%
which means it's very very important
if you look at other sections, so CPQ platform
has the highest weightage
so they expect you to design, configure,
troubleshoot, pricing rules
using lookup objects and formula fields
to meet the  business requirement
which is very basic  and he had very important
apply understanding of the code calculation sequence
i will talk about it right, when we reach to this, this topic so don't worry about it
like i said if it sounds jogging to you guys
just don't worry about it for today right
then you need to know how to, to you know demonstrate
the knowledge about CPQ object data model
as it relates to data migration right
set up CPQ for localization and multi-currency
for international customers and users right
so, i will talk about it right i will cover each and every topic
so, that's CPQ platform then you need to know bundle configuration
17% which is still pretty important
you're given a scenario sort of a bundle structure to meet
the business requirements, so it's all about the bundles right
so, we will look into that
then we have pricing which is very important
so, you know, talk about expect the price outcomes and other stuff
templates 7% still important
product selection, you know search filters and custom actions, pretty important still, right
order, contracts, amendments, renewals, 15%
very important
then you need to know about the products
demonstrate how to set up products, price books
price book entries and approval process right
so, the expectation is that by the time
you know you clear the certification,
you should be very well aware of all these topics
if you're not that means that you haven't studied very well right
so, like  i always say right, take certification
as an opportunity to learn something new, right
it's not just to pass or fail, right
i mean, you might pass, you might fail it doesn't matter
are you  having fun in the journey? that's important right
and along with the fun, are you learning something new? right
you know that's the way i look at  it
for me, yes i do understand right, you're investing 200 bucks it's  important to pass the certification
but people do fail right, and if you fail for whatever reason
just take it as a learning opportunity and move on, right
try again, so that's the way it is
and right so, the topic what we're going  to cover right, so let me show you that
i'll be teaching on trailhead,
as you know right, most of the stuffs are covered in trailhead
and plus i'm going to bring some of the real life experience
as well so, it's going to be fun right
we're going  to do hands-on we're going to do theory
so we're going to do some fun stuff together right,
so it's going to be an interesting journey
i'm really looking  forward to you
okay so, prepare for your salesforce CPQ certification uh sorry specialist credentials
i have to mention CPQ specialist right,
because it's a specialist certification
right so overview, we already talked about it,
so the first part is pretty much knocked off
so, we are in the sweet spot, right
then the CPQ platform we can talk about basics
important features, installation, settings, sorry the package settings
page layouts, object relationship, mapping custom fields between objects
translating salesforce CPQ records
then we talk about bundles, product bundles, right
all this stuff  right, excuse me, pricing information,
product selection, so yeah it's gonna be fun all right,
i can tell you that CPQ is extremely interesting
it's really exciting topic right, you guys really gonna have fun
and yes it's it can be challenging at time,
but it is really fun
to, to do stuff in CPQ
just one thing i wanted to tell you guys right,
i do understand that right
you know, i'm giving this certification free, right
so, that's fine because i love to give it back
to the salesforce community
in saying so, i do expect you guys to, you know
form a study group or you know read from trailhead
because just don't assume, that right i'm just making a video
so you watch my video and you know just go
and sit in the certification and you'll clear it
it's not going to happen guys,
you have to put  your own time, right
you have to spend time to understand,
you have to read the documentation, you have to do hands-on
you're right, it's an investment right
so you have to be proactive
you can't expect me that right, i'm just gonna make entire video
and then i'll assume that you guys are pretty sweet to go,
it's it's not gonna happen like that, right
so you guys have to put your own time and effort
and till you guys don't do it,
then the certification is going to be very difficult
i'll be very upfront right
so, yeah that's that's pretty much i wanted
to cover in today's episode
so, tomorrow what we're going to do,
we're going to start looking at the CPQ basics
so it's going to take us right, roughly around... maybe 15 hours
right, so we'll see how we go right
so, i don't want to rush right, i wanted to give you guys enough time
so even in in my previous certification right
the service cloud, you might have seen that  i've been doing quite slow
the reason why i'm being doing quite slower
because i want you guys to you know
have enough time to read the material
to, to do different things to practice before you you know,
start working on the next topic
so usually, i would say if you are pretty new to CPQ
you will need at least three to four months
at  least a preparation, you cannot clear it  just by doing 15 days
i just hate to break this to you guys
you cannot clear CPQ certification with zero experience in 15 days
if that's what you are aspiring to be
it's, i mean, you might pass but what's the point? right
so i would highly encourage you guys to spend at least two to three months
if you are new to CPQ
if you're experienced, if you have a lot of experience then you'll smash it up even in a week
so you don't have to worry much so
yeah so that's pretty much i wanted to  talk about in today's episode
thank you