good everyone, i hope you guys have an amazing day
so today i want to briefly touch on what CPQ is all about
we're going to register for an org
and i'm going to talk about a licensing  aspect as well
right, the reason why i wanted to mention about the licensing aspect
i remember someone recently pointed out to me
that you know whenever i talk about a functionality,
it's good to talk about the licensing aspect
so i like, yeah fair enough that's a valid point
so the first thing first right
i just wanted to, you know in the last episode i, i mentioned
about the certification and exam guide
so, today i will talk about, what exactly CPQ is all  about
why do you need CPQ, right
we'll talk about a fictitious scenario
and we'll create an org,
and yeah, and probably create a quote
so that's pretty  much i'm gonna cover today
all right, so what is CPQ right
CPQ stand for three things one is the C, P, and Q right
so C stand for configure
P stand for price
and the Q stand for quote right
the C... when we talk about configure it's like
you pick out what they will buy i mean your customer will buy
and P is for price it just,
you know it's the product price obviously, right
and the Q is for quote, that's the quote
which you normally send to the  customer
now, you must be wondering right,
what the heck is the quote, right
so, to explain that
you know, i just have to give you a scenario but,
in saying that i will talk about briefly
about what quote is about
right so, say for instance you have a customer
okay, the customer comes to you and say, i wanted a quote
now, if you're not sure what a quote is you must be
wondering what the heck the customer is asking
but most likely, that's not the case but in general i'm  saying
so what quote is about, they wanted to know
the details about a potential purchase
right, such as what they will be getting
and how much they will be paying
and also the terms and conditions,
so that's in a nutshell a quote is all about, okay
the product is the products you add
example for instance customer wants to buy
you know  the 10, you know 10
bottles of beers so that's a product
so you categorize you can, products can be bundled
that's a different thing
so menti... talk about a bit, and we have the price you know the price
the price associated with the product
right so, yeah so this is in a nutshell the CPQ is about
but that's that's not enough yet
so because i, i do understand that you must be thinking
that but this information means nothing to me right
so if i'm a consultant, or so for instance if i'm a company
i... you know i use salesforce but
you know, why should i go for CPQ
when we have everything else in place
okay, so i'll give a scenario
so for instance i run a brewing  company okay
so we brew different beers like IPAs stouts, lagers, right
now, we have a few customers so for instance
this is a fictional company right,
so the company based in Wellington
so we got a few customers, say for instance customers from Oakland
customers from wellington, customers from, crashes, customers from Australia
like for instance Melbourne um or Sydney right
now, there are some customers
which are long-term customers
like australian customers they often buy in bulk
they buy a lot of things
so, based on that, you know if
we give a different price to them it's like a discount
and you know the same product cost different in Australia
because of the currency difference, right
now, so what what happened right,
initially you know as a company
we builds the product pricing information
in a separate system
which is often accessed by...
the team who looks after the pricing information
unfortunately the sales team
do not have access to the system
so what normally happens is,
when the sales guy requests for an information
the admin of their pricing system often
generate a pdf and send to the,
to the sales guy
or you can do, also do excel documentation
which is fine
now, we hit a snag eventually
where you know, there were three sales guys,
new sales guy we hired recently
and we have to, you know offer
different pricing to a brewery from Sydney
different pricing from brewery uh from Oakland
as and as well as a brewing from Christchurch
now, uh one of the sales guys reached out to
the pricing team and say
hey i'm looking  for the pricing for IPA's
say the customer requesting for like
you know 800 bottles of IPA beers
so, and i'm planning to give discount so
can you send me the updated pricing information?
so you know they decided okay
the, the pricing team sent the information
in the form of pdf, the sales team is happy
now, for whatever reason right
the pricing team has updated the price on some beers
so, now what happened?
after they updated,
the sales guy who
requested for the pdf was a week ago
didn't get the latest  copy of a pdf
right, so obviously he was working the old copy
and the other two sales members
right, they got the latest copy
now, obviously you know, right the salespeople
not necessarily have to talk  to each other right
it's like if you're a salesperson
you obviously won't go and ask
hey what's your pricing model
what's  your pricing all right
obviously don't do that
so the so, as a matter of fact to keep the story short
the first salesperson got that outdated information
and he created a quote and
send the quote to the customer with an old
with a different pricing model
and when the customer received the  information customers like
hey, this is not what i've been told
i've been told a different pricing model
i discussed just now with the
with the senior executive from
your brewing company and they said
you'll be getting a different pricing model
and you guys send me entirely different one what we agreed on
and the sales guy's like, oh that's crap
we don't have the latest information
and  the sales guy go back to the pricing team
and say hey can you send me the latest pdf please
so the guy, the team sent him the latest PDF and see all totally different pricing model
so, now you see the discrepancy right
and, now this has caused
a frustration among your customer
and the customer started to think
these guys are, are they trying to cheat me?
or they're trying to fool me?,
because they said something to me
they said very different information
when i spoke to one of their account executive
on the phone, now they're sending me a different quote
it just seems pretty shady it's, so you know,
that can cause a frustration among the customer
now imagine, that's one thing
and another thing, you know we
have a quote creating system
which is you know in a different system again
so, the customer has to, so the sales team
has to reload the information
into the new system, and then generate the quote, right
so, it's like a duplicate of information
that's floating around
and also there's a risk that the sales team
may not have the updated pricing
information on a product
so, and if you look at it  from us,
from a thousand feet above right
you might see oh it's a very
simple problem to have
but from a customer perspective
it's a misleading information
and also from a business reputation point of view
it's a big thing to, to have
i mean, or i mean, i would say
it's the worst thing to have
you know, when the customer
started getting annoyed right
because you know if customer,
if a customer get annoyed
they might go and say to another client
hey i don't trust that brewing company
because  they tell something on the phone
and when they send out the quote they,
they try to cheat you with the wrong quote
so, to solve that problem, right
we have something called CPQ right,
CPQ is integrated with the salesforce
you don't have to use different system
data resides in the salesforce
so you know people with the right access can
access the information from the same data source
which is from a salesforce object
so you see how cool is that, right
and already we're using ourselves for so,
you know so with an extra license
it just worked wonders for us,
and also it saves the thrust
it saves a lot of sales time, sales rep time
to go and  request you know the
pdf or excel from a pricing team
so they don't have to do that anymore
they just can access everything from a single
store, or in other words from a single software right
from a salesforce, so that's one advantage
now that's a very major advantage though right
because salesforce offers a lot of things
in when it comes to CPQ
you know, we talk about quotes,
we talk  about products
just now mentioned, we talk about the prices
you know, we can generate the quotes in a pdf form
and also, you can also, do the contracts and renewals
if you have a subscription-based model
we're going to talk about everything in detail
when it reached the stage,
but today just an overview, so
i hope this is clear when
i try to explain from a business point of view
my apologies if, if the example
looks a bit shady
but you know,
i think beer example is pretty cool
right, because obviously customers try
to buy a lot of beers from a brewery
so obviously they're interested
to have, to get the quote
right to see like if i buy 800
so what's the discount will be like
what's the pricing right, so they wanted
to get that information before
you know, the opportunity
get converted into an order
right so, it is a very streamlined process
when, when you talk about CPQ
now, CPQ like i said it's not free okay
so obviously if you have a
salesforce org, you have to buy
you have to pay for the license okay
so for our demo what i'm going to do
i will register for an org
so as you can see the screen, on the screen right
so now, if you look at the pricing information
right, it's all online
so, okay i'm not interested in chatting right
so CPQ right 75 bucks USD
you're not talking about new zealand dollars
you're not talking about australian money
you're talking about american dollars, right
yeah, i mean i don't want to get
into the currency argument
this is what it is,
it's an american company
so american money, right
pretty sweet
all right, so configure
price and quote software right
you get it for 75 bucks
per user and paid monthly, right
then you have CPQ plus
you can configure, price and, quote software
with increased process control and automation
so, this is another thing
and then you have CPQ billing and growth
so which is you have to request a quote
and create quote to cash...  cash solution
this is a, this most companies might be interested in this
so for that you have to contact salesforce, right
so now if you look at the, the functionality right
a lot of things quote to cash offers
like configure, pricing, quoting
which is pretty common to all the...
the model licensing options we have
enhanced products, catalogs and price book,
because price book is very important
and i believe you know, if you are a small brewery and...
i will encourage you to start with the basic
to see if it really fits the requirement
uh that's the reason why we have a
trailhead org, you can, you can you know
go and fiddle with it to see
if it really meets your requirement
so, these two options will
pretty much do the job for you
in saying that, you might also need
advanced approval and order management
so you might need to go for CPQ plus
or if you also might need usage-based pricing
so you might CPQ plus a it's a great option
but if you're after invoicing and revenue schedules
then you might have to go for,
along with all the other options we discuss
then you have to go for CPQ & billing growth
that in saying so, if you're after complex revenue reporting
automated payments in a location
then you have to go for CPQ & billing plus
and for that you have to request a quote
so that's in a nutshell
about the licensing model, all right
i hope that's clear i don't want
to miss out the licensing part
just to make you guys understand
it's not a free stuff to use
so you have to pay for it right
so  that's cool all right
now how to register for an org right
obviously you know, i assume
that you guys are preparing for certification
so most of the students or even if you're working
you know in CPQ space you might want to try it out yourself
it's it's good to have an org ready
so that you guys can practice
which is fantastic
so what do you have to do, right
go to this place called...
i'll put the link in the description below so don't worry
don't stress yourself for you know,
to write it down, don't worry about it
i'll put the link in the description
so go to this link you know
trailhead.salesforce.com, CPQ trail
so you just fill in the details
it's just like any other org
registration which you've done before
pretty simple, pretty consistent,
it's not a rocket science right
nothing fancy here, all right
so once you fill in you'll get an email
you, you click on to verify your account
enter your password
you're good to go, you're in an org
so i'm in org, so most likely
what happens you will not see the CPQ,
when you log into your ORG
so if you don't see it
you might see something else so
what you can do, go to this tic tac toe icon
and you will see CPQ, Salesforce CPQ org
okay so select that and you
will get these options here
you get opportunities which is pretty important
obviously when we talk about CPQ
we talk about opportunities a lot, right
so you create a quote,
i'll show you how to do that
it's very simple
then you have orders, how you create an order,
we have products obviously
CPQ is incomplete without a product
then your product rules different
products rules that comes into place
how to configure it, i will talk about it
when we reach to that stage
but for now just, just you know,
don't worry about it okay for now
then we have pricing rules so
different pricing rules right
summary variables,
then you have more options like quote terms
you know quote templates
we'll look at  all of these things right
because you know the certification
covers a lot of things
so today is just an introduction
okay, so go to opportunity
i mean, i can pick any
opportunities i want right
so i'll choose this opportunity,
all opportunity
a camera for marketing team right,
whatever that is
okay, you already have a quote right
and this is a primary quote
so you can only have
one primary quote for opportunity
right remember that
now how to create a quote right,
now you must be thinking okay
so... what we can do?
you can go to new so,
i'll start fresh with the, with the new...
opportunity, let's say which one has a...
it, maybe it doesn't have one
that's just support for
all right so you know what
we're just gonna,
delete this one
don't care
all right so you will get something like this
when you create a new opportunity, right
opportunity can contain...
many quotes right, so, now so, you so
most of the things just,
you will  not find this configuration
if you are using a normal developer org
because, this is a CPQ org
so that's why you can see quotes
you can see contracts
you can see renewable contracts
you can see different stuff right
all right so i'm going to show you
how to create a quote
so, quote is like a pdf document
you send out to your customer
pretty simple
it contains information about
the product, pricing, terms of agreement
nothing fancy, right
okay so, go to quote here, and go to new
so we'll say buy some, what um...
so if i wanted to make primary,
just make a primary
select this checkbox to designate
this quote as a primary
one on the opportunity
and sync quote line with
the opportunity line item
so it will sync your quote line
with an opportunity line items,
just remember that, right
so for now it's all right
i'm, i'm happy with that
so obviously you search an opportunity
uh which one is the right, okay
i will say okay, desktop computers
for supporting agents
accounts i'm just going to
choose the Dave account
Dave Muller and sales rep
i honestly, okay i choose my name
why not right
and i'm not really concerned
about any of the stuff at this stage
because we  will talk about it
but today's the main idea is to just to show you
how simple is to create a quote
okay so, that's all we are focusing on today
click on save
it's not rocket science guys right i mean
there's nothing complicated about it
it's just, you have to understand the  concept
why you have to do it, right
so that's the main thing,
because you will be
working as a consultant
you have to explain to the customer
why they should go for CPQ
if you come and tell me, right
it does the quote,
it does the product line
i said, well we have our own
in-house software which does that very well
so you have to,
as a consultant here, right
you have to understand the pros and cons
and you have to compare their software
and then come up with you know your
reasoning you know to suggest customer
that, hey go for CPQ
and that's why you have to
have full understanding
about the licensing model
pricing it's very important
okay so, edit lines
right, so i'm going to go to edit lines
here we're going to add quote
products i'm going to add
a few a couple of products right
so add products,
so you can add a group
but i'm just adding products
that's simple
okay so what i'm going to do?...
notebook, hopefully i have some
or no, computer
okay i'm just going to choose the
desktop computer that's pretty much cool
i'm just going to select it
and, all right so
when you choose the
desktop computer, right
see what, it do it will show you
all of these prices right
it's like a product bundle, okay
so, i'll show you
look at that
and, okay so all i wanted was a
a desktop computer
but along with the desktop computer
it says hey do you want
you know the cpu, the ram,
the keyboard, the mouse
it comes as a bundle
it's a product bundle
so, a product bundle contains
say, in simple terms, like keyboard
sorry, a computer,
computer desktop will include
mouse, keyboard, maybe webcam
you know
so these all can be sold as a bundle, right
it's just a one product bundle
so, so this is a desktop computer
and it just sold us, just one bundle
that all of this stuff here
okay so, let's say
i wanted to add another product
just to give you an idea
okay so let's say i will add another one
so i'll just add another mouse
let's say i wanted to add another mouse right
i choose this mouse and i say select, right
all right, so it's added by itself right
i mean, because it doesn't come as a bundle
because you know,
yes it is a part of a computer
but, when you buy a mouse
nobody asks you, hey do you want
to buy a computer laptop with it
it doesn't work right
so when you buy a laptop
or when you buy a desktop computer
they often ask hey do you want a mouse,
do you want a keyboard
right, if you if you buy the chassis right
i mean i'm not sure if many people
uses the desktop computer today but
let's say for the sake of
argument people do, right
so this is how you know, the bundles are configured
i hope the explanation is clear because
i wanted to make you guys understand right
you know, say a customer comes
to you and request the quote
so you know, these are the things
that you include as a quote
and the customer will want to know
what they're going to get
and what the price will be like
what's the terms and conditions
fantastic right
save
all right now
you can preview the document
so, so you'll see
how the document will look like
and how you're going
to send to the customer so
this is how you're
going to send to the customer
so there's a sales person
description i mean
for now it's fine
and the terms and  condition
this is what you're going
to send to the customer
and the customer
will be happy with it
so you create an order
and you know
you ship the stuff to the customer
so that's how in simple terms
the things goes behind the scene
as you can see it's pretty simple
it's pretty handy you,
i don't have to go to
you know different
team to request
for a price
of a product,
i don't have to go anywhere
you know outside this
specific software
to you know look for...
you know, different products
right, so i don't have to look for a different
software to look for opportunity to link  to
so it's all in one place
it's all a part of a single software
that's advantage Salesforce brings
so this is  why i believe
that CPQ is very important
so even the customers
are using their in-house
just one, one thing i wanted to highly
recommend you guys,
just do not suggest CPQ
without understanding their
in-house system right
i have seen consultants
you know especially, not just in CPQ
they say hey, can you go
and take this one
can you go and take that one
if i'm a customer i will say, well
have you even seen
what we have in house
first of all right
so if you're a consultant
or you know specialist
whatever you call yourself
it becomes your responsibility
to understand first of all
the problem the customer is facing
then you propose a solution
don't propose a solution first
and then try to understand the solution
that's a very bad way to do that
you might find it funny
but i've seen people doing that as well
so so that's pretty much i wanted to...
talk about in today's episode
i hope you  guys enjoyed it
if you have any questions
please feel free to ask me anytime right
have a great day, adios