good everyone i hope you guys
have an  amazing day
so what i'm gonna do today i will talk about
the package settings
which comes with the CPQ
my apologies
it's been a while that i've done
any video on CPQ, right
the reason being i've been unwell
for a you know, for a couple of weeks
because i've been down with influenza
so yeah, so i was not able to talk
because my lungs is still healing
so in saying that
i won't be making a very long video today
so i will do short videos
you know over the course of time
i'm gonna get back to making
you know longer duration videos
okay, so when you install CPQ, right
if you if you remember
i talked about in the last episode
CPQ you can go to the trial
and install it, right
it's usually for 90 days
pretty simple
now CPQ, when you install CPQ
typically comes with a few settings
which is worth to know
because you tampering with those
will have a profound impact the way you
work with CPQ
so, i thought, i investigate, sorry
i spent some time
to explain to you guys
what the settings are about
we won't be covering
everything today
but i will talk about a few, right
okay, so i logged into my org
so i hope you guys have registered for CPQ org
if you do not know how to do that
please watch my previous episode
i talked about it in detail, right
okay so, under quick find
i go... installed packages
all right so you can see
that CPQ is installed, right
and it's still active
and you can see the expiration date
it's not set which is fine for now
okay so i'm gonna go to configure
so we will look at a few settings
so, documents right
we got different options
there now you must be wondering
oh wow that's a lot of settings
yeah, it comes with a lot of settings
but it will be good to know
what the settings are
first start with the document folder, right
the first one
so it contains a few options
so the document folders
what that means is that uh it
lets you select the folder
which contains the quote document after generation
so  you remember i talked about
i demonstrated last episode
how to create a quote, right
so once the quote is generated
it has to go somewhere, right
so that's what you set it here
you can go into quote folder
you can go in under personal documents
salesforce CPQ assets
SteelBrick CPQ template resources, right
so that's nothing
attachment target uh so
you choose target object, right
so say for instance
by default is opportunity
so when you choose opportunity
what happens is the quote documents, right
which they are usually  saved
in the chosen salesforce document folder
and in the opportunity
notes and attachment related lists
right, so usually when the quotes get you know
generator righ,t so you chose this document folder
so it goes there
along with that
it goes to your opportunity
related list, right, notes attachment
now, if you decide to choose the quote right
so you must be wondering okay so
what that what we'll do what, sorry
what that will do right,
if you select quote
so when you select aquote, right
the quote documents as usual
they usually saved in the
chosen salesforce documentation
along with that
it also goes into the quotes notes
and attachment related list
it's pretty simple, right
now if you select document only, so
it just pretty much only stores
into the, you know document
folder which you selected
it's pretty simple, right
now, hide document name
so if you wanted to hide the file name
on a quote document you can do that
so it's usually helpful
when you if you don't want the
you know the sales team to
fiddle uh with the document name
or change it for whatever reason, right
so usually you know,
it comes with the default name, right
now if the sales reps right
they say okay i don't want the
default name i wanted to change it
so if you if you tick this one, right
they will not be able to do that
right, so that's pretty simple right
post to feed
so now you must be wondering right
a few of the options are tick,
yeah that's by default
uh comes with that, but
you know the reason why i'm talking about this settings
so that you know you guys understand right
if you have a business requirement
where you wanted to implement the CPQ
you need to know this settings
so that you can make best use of the CPQ
so uh but just  don't rely on the
default options that's been given to you, right
when you install this product
okay now post to feed
as usual the name indicates
pretty simple
it posts the quote document the chatter feed
which is associated with the quote
or opportunity attachment target
okay so that's pretty much about it
so full page review, if you can do... preview sorry
full page preview
it previews the quote document in a full window
instead of a small iframe right
that's pretty much it
as you can see that my voice
is still not very clear
my apologies for that
i mean like i said i'm still recovering so
it will get better i mean
i mean if you would have heard me
a couple of uh you know
last week i got like a horse voice right
it just sounded pretty strange
and i you know one of my co-workers said
hey you sound like a very different person
i mean even though i work from home but
still right when you talk in teams
so anyways sorry daggers
okay so enable multi-language translation
this is pretty interesting though right
so, what that will do if you tick this option
uh it will allows the sales rep
to generate the quote documentation
in one of your org supported language right
your work might support spanish
you might support italian
much about korean right over right
so what that will do this will add a locale pick list
to the generated document page okay
so, but the but the problem is
uh not the problem
but there's something
which you have to keep into consideration
you must also have
translator values stored for
the language that they can select
okay so that's that's pretty much it
okay now,
there's something called mass document username
now you must be wondering oh, this is a click...
you know request authorization okay
so, so what does that mean right
if you click that button
it will allow salesforce CPQ
to generate and send
quote documents on your behalf
when you're not logged into the salesforce
so if you want that functionality
then go for it
i mean this setting appears only upon
the the first installation okay
so uh so, if you select this one
this options goes away,
so when you select it
you're just telling the salesforce CPQ hey
generate the, the quote and
you know send document on my behalf
and i'm not logged in so
if that's your business requirement
go and select it
if you tick it,
then you can't roll back
probably you might have to
call the support i'm not 100% sure
um so then we have the
group package settings, right
this is... not too much
in the sense right,
you don't see much options there
i mean you need to understand solution groups
i'll talk about solution group
in the coming episode
but just remember for the sake of...
you know understanding at the stage
that if you enable this option right
it will allow admins to create
solution group for the sales reps
to use in the code line editor
yeah like if you see in the quote right
so we have a quote and we have
you know the header
then we have lines right
where you add  different stuff to it
so the solution group
the you know the functionality
of solution group in nutshell, right
it will  let you group
and subtotal products
independently of other quote line item
and the quote line groups
so if your company has a standard set
of quote line group like
say solar panel hardware or say solar panel software
or you can say solar panel different  stuff
if you have a separate lines of grouping
then this will be handy
i'll talk about it right
when i get to this stage just for now
just just don't worry about it
just just understand one thing
you tick this option
you will allow admin to create
he you know the the solution group
for your app okay so that it can
be used in the uh quote line editor
simple right, okay now require group name
okay this is by default ticked
um so what happens is, right
when this  option is ticked
sales reps are required to...
so when you  when you tick this
it will allow the sales rep
to edit group names
in the quote line editor
so, so require group names so yeah
so sales reps are required to edit
group names in the quote line editor, so
that's um then we have um
lime editor package settings
it's a lot of them
i understand that
um so let's see
we talk about the plugins right
i'm  gonna talk about
uh line editor it's a bit complicated
so i don't want to go too deep into it
uh just gonna talk about few things right
uh which is gonna be commonly used
electronic signature plug-in
for instance this one
so what that will do is right
um it lets you integrate salesforce CPQ
with electronic e-signature provider
like for instance kundasign
if you wanted to
you know integrate your CPQ with you
know kundasign, you can do that
then you have uh you know something called
product search plugin
so it lets you modify and add
specif uh to uh you know
specification specification
i can't pronounce the word
specificity to product filter searches
and it will pretty much help you with you know
the search stuff
so i haven't used this functionality so much
so i can't really get into the detail
but i've used electronic signature a lot
um then i've used the quote calculator plugin
that i've used in so you know
you can extend the
functionality of the salesforce
CPQ calculator
so you can use it here
so i've used that one
but product search plug-in not really so
i can but this is a functionality there
so um yeah
and then the order management
plug-in is there so which is another
important stuff then we have just
you know so order management plug-in
it lets you customize you know sales
how your salesforce CPQ
calculate normally the order start date
so if you're you know if you wanted to
work on your order start date
so this is the plugin
to go for it
so that's the order management plugin
then we have, document store plugin
which is, which is another plug-in
which is i believe very important
i've seen often integration
with that plug-in a lot
in CPQ based on my experience
working this CPQ implementation before
so it lets you integrate your CPQ with  you know
document management providers right
so whichever you choose
so that's.. then we have pricing and calculation
which is another one
i will touch a little bit on pricing  and calculation
so now the first one is the currency symbol right
now you must be wondering what
the heck is the currency symbol so
so if you so CPQ right, it uses this currency symbol
in the quote line editor
on the generated document right
like a dollar sign or whatever right
so  that's pretty much it
and then you have something
called unit price scale
which is very important right
because the this is very important
so this is a fractional unit price round off to
many decimal places right so this two here
so that's a bit that's, you can change it
if you wanted to change it
then you have something called
by default the legacy calculator
so this enable the
salesforce CPQ legacy calculator
but you have to understand one thing
salesforce CPQ no longer offer support
for this version of the calculator
so it's better to untick
yeah, so....
now you must be wondering
oh this is too much right
i understand
we haven't touched detail
in in detail about pricing
about discounting model calculation
we're gonna get there but
just wanted to understand that
we have these settings in place
so it will make you
use CPQ in, in a much informed way right
then we have very important
thing, enable quick calculate
so this is this one this boy here
so when you tick this option right
it actually um so
i'll tell you one thing what
does this do right in simple terms
so this functionality right
this specific functionality it
actually improves your code calculation time
and how does that do that
so it's pretty simple
it disables three function, uh features
one is the price rule
in quote line formula field
that depends upon the parent relationship
and displaying role-up summary fields
in the quote line  editor so
if you wanted to use this
those three things will be disabled
price rules, quote line formula fields
displaying roll-up summary fields
in the quote line editor
so this is how it improves the
the the calculation time right
so now you must be wondering oh there's
different things so
i mean for now this is all i think
you should pay attention to it
i know the subscriptions and renew renewal
so if you if you are if you you know go and
buy like it's like in a magazine right
you buy for 12 months subscription
so i get order renewed after 12 months so
so yeah so different options comes into places
this is a little bit more to talk about it
so i'm not going to talk about today because
unfortunately i'm already getting tired
so  i will stop it right here now
and in the next episode
hopefully tomorrow, day after tomorrow
i will cover the remaining part of it right
sounds good i hope
so yeah i mean
from exam point of view this is important
so one thing i always tell right
when i teach people certification
my main goal is not to you know teach you guys
just to clear the certification
but to enjoy the journey
understand the product very well
and become a better consultant or an architect
right that's all my intention is all about
right so that being said
i hope you guys have an  amazing  wednesday  anyway