good everyone
i hope you guys have an amazing day
so in the last episode i spoke about
CPQ configuration package settings
i did  mention about the few tabs
the documents groups and
and plug-ins so, what i'm gonna do today, right
i'm not gonna cover everything
because it's not really required
for you to know at this stage
so i will talk about few aspects of it, right
so for instance
let's look at the line editor
and we're going to talk about
the options which is tick by default
like you know visualize product hierarchy
preserve bundle structure
keep bundle together
enable multi-line delete right
so multi-line delete
okay so that's a  pretty simple option right
so if you  enable that option
so what that will do
it will help the sales rep
to multiselect quote lines
and then delete it
that's pretty much it
so you know you can select multiple lines
and then you can delete, okay
and then we have something called
visual product hierarchy
which is pretty simple
so it will intend the
components of the bundle together
so, which also includes your nested bundles
so  you know this feature right
this is a pretty important feature
it will actually makes your bundle easier to read
especially if they have
many product options, right
um so that's one thing right so that's
that's why it's ticked by default
then we have preserve bundle structure
so, so it will display bundles products options
in the same order in the renewable quotes
right, so now you must be wondering um
that doesn't make sense so,
this  feature is useful right in simple terms
if you organize your bundles
with important or frequently
edited product options at the beginning of the bundle
that's pretty much it right
okay and keep the bundle together
that's that's pretty simple right
when you drag and drop a bundle
parent to a different locations
in a quote line editor
Salesforce CPQ moves it's component to the
new  quote line positions as well
so that's pretty much it
excuse me!
so now let's look at the um
the subscriptions and renewals
i don't want to talk much about
because the reason why i don't want to talk
because there's not much we're
going to talk about at this stage
so, and the only thing i would
in general would love to uh talk about
is that the use of the legacy
amend and the renewal service
that this one
so you know in summer 19 or later right
the scale amendment
and amendment and renewable service, you know
just, just got enabled by default
so  it's it's a new service right
so it offers you know
improved support of amendment
and renewable actions of contracts
with  large volume of you know the related  records
right now
to revert to the previous you know uh
service functionality so we tick this one
so that's pretty much it says
continue using legacy contract service, so
if you wanted to use the old legacy
renew service then tick this by default
you know, when you install the CPQ package
it comes ticked
so if you wanted to use the old service
keep on doing it that's fine
like i said it's based on your business requirement
so we're going to talk about it later
CPQ is a vast topic right
so we will be covering different aspects of it
and as we uncover different you know parts of CPQ
we will be revisiting some
of the package settings
so don't worry we will cover again
okay so i just want to mention a couple of them
so like disable initial quote sync
by default when a salesforce rep
sales trip right, creates the first quote
from an opportunity salesforce CPQ
creates quotes lines for each of the opportunities
opportunity product so if you tick this, right
so if i make this tick, right
what will happen is
salesforce CPQ
does not create quote line
for this opportunity products
that's pretty much it,  right
the same goes for the disable quote
contact defaulting
so when the sales reps
makes a quote from an opportunity
the quote doesn't inherit its
primary contact from the opportunity, right
the  sales rep or  you know whoever is
enters the quote primary contact in um instantly
so um deletions it's pretty simple
you know you can delete product
options from the prior quotes
so that's what it is
and so as you can see that
we have an option called allow multiple orders
so you know  your sales rep can split
a quote, quote lines into
multiple orders right
obviously you can only do using CPQ, right
you can't do without CPQ so that's
the and if you tick this
you can do the multiple orders
so yeah i mean that's pretty much
i wanted to talk about
in today's episode
i mean, i do  understand that you must be thinking
oh  you've got a lot of options here
but you don't have to know at this stage
trust me you don't have to know at this stage
you're at the beginning stage of CPQ
i don't want it to overwhelm you
guys with too many options
so whatever i've covered for now
that's good enough for
us to move forward
and as we you know progress through the quotes
we might revisit these options again, right
so that's pretty much
i wanted to cover in this episode
as you can see that my
voice is still a bit clunky
i mean, i'm still recovering from cough
i tell you guys cough is
the worst thing to get, right
if it's the first thing to come in and the last
thing to move right leave your body so
yeah i mean i've been battling
with this cough for like
almost two and a half weeks now
ever since i got that
influenza right so but
i think i'm getting better so yeah
so that's that being said
i hope you guys have an amazing day, adios