good everyone i hope you guys have an  amazing day so today what i'm gonna do i  will show you how to group  uh a product by you know  different field like for instance using  product id or  a product code or active status now you  must be wondering where this option  uh will be used and why do i have to  even worry about it right okay so if you  remember you know i often talked about  codes how you can add products to the  codes so for instance let me go to this  code right  and say i will say edit lines  it's a pretty simple option but it's yet  very powerful so you know sometimes  customer might ask you hey can i uh you  know group by a different field so you  know it's good to know so if i do add  products right  um you usually see here  you know there's no grouping here  right it's just a you know list of  products so what if i wanted to say  group by say a  product code  right or say i wanted to buy  you know  an active status  or something else is that possible even  right you must be wondering yeah  absolutely it's possible now how to do  that is pretty simple if you remember uh  i initially talked about the package  settings you know when you install cpq  you know there are different you know  the package settings you have to worry  about it so one of the one i want to  talk about so now to go to this package  settings pretty simple right you just go  to the setup  and uh under let me show you how to  restart go to setup  and under that  uh go to install packages right  and if you go to install packages  um  you can pretty much look at configure  right and once you configure it will  take you here pretty simple now go to  the additional settings now this is the  one you should be paying attention to  the product result group field name so  right now set to none  let's say i wanted to change it to say  product code okay  so i wanted to group this you know the  field by protocol so i'm gonna do save  um  hopefully it's gonna save  and  let me see let me refresh it  see if it saved really saved  i always like to double check  you know before okay so it's saved  now i will go here and just refresh this  page as well  and  all right okay now go to add products  see the difference here you see  now it's um  a group by product code right so you can  expand it and you can see the product  here right  so or let's say you wanted to group by  an actives  uh you know just to see  uh  you know you might have a requirement  where i only wanted to see the product  which are active and i wanted to group  them by active flag okay a pretty  interesting requirement so you can do  that as well so you go back to the same  settings  right product result group field name  uh and change it to active i'm going to  save it  i just wanted to  uh  so once i saved it let's see if it's  saved properly  it's always good to double check  so go to additional settings fantastic  all right so go to code and refresh this  page  and  right just a second  and i will see add products  and you see this is an active state  okay i'll just minimize it see i only  have active products so uh it will show  you  active product status right  now  you know this will be handy if you  wanted to group by active or negative  right  um  uh similarly you can group based on your  you know business requirement group by  different field right  so this is very handy in my opinion and  you know you might get a requirement  from a customer where they say hey i  wanted to group this product by  different fields right and is it  possible because most of the time  customers may not be aware of the  settings so it's good to know right and  even it's good to know from an exam  point of view as well so that's pretty  much i wanted to cover in today's  episode i hope you guys have an amazing  tuesday adios