good everyone i hope you guys have an  amazing day so today i'm going to talk  about another pricing method that's the  cost plus uh markup pricing so this is a  pretty simple concept right so  what that have so in this scenario um  the cost plus market pricing it's  uh a sales rep will often have  uh advantage when it comes to  controlling the pricing instead of you  know you let this  cpq decides the price for the product  uh so for instance what happens is that  sales uh rep can't start  uh the product with the base price  that's the cost price and then he you  know he or she can use the markup  or  adjust it using a percentage  so say for instance um  uh if you wanted to buy say a computer  for  uh say a cost price of  so if you say for instance a sales  person wants to sell a computer uh so  the desktop computer cost price is like  two thousand dollars and the sales rep  wants to add  uh you know two percent markup on top of  it so  that's how the cost and markup works is  pretty simple configuration it you know  it's just like few clicks so  yeah okay so what i'll do i'll go to the  product so let's pick up a  any product  um so  so i'll go to the products  and uh  say  okay phone case right  just an example  so we have price book  20 bucks so what i'll do  uh i will  go to show all  and there's something called cost  right i will add new  uh and i will say the unit cost just say  17  okay  and then i will scroll down  and change the  the pricing method to cost  yeah  that's pretty much you have to do it's  pretty simple then you go to code  um and  actually  hang on a second  it's a great i will copy this one  and then go to code  and i will take this code  and  edit lines  uh what i'll do i will remove  all the existing uh products from the  code  so that we can  start the clean slate so just remove  this  and i will say delete lines  okay  uh add products  and i will do  this one  i selected okay so remember i  so here it shows 20 bucks but when you  add it  right it will  give you that 17 bucks because it's  coming from the the cost price because  you're using  um  the car pricing method as a cost so it  will pick up your cost price okay  now if i'm a sales rep i wanted to add  uh my commission on top of it so i would  say i'll go here right this arrow right  arrow so i'll have a markup  so i will say i want to add  uh 10  so that means 1.7 right as the  commission or as a markup  so i will save it  okay sorry let me go back  um okay so you can see  18.70 that's 17  uh  percent sorry 10 of 17 that's 1.7  so it's like 17 plus 1.7 that's 18.7  right so that's how it works so as you  can see it's pretty simple um yeah so we  have different pricing methods right  in cpq but the way to use it it depends  on your business requirement and the  client requirement right  um so obviously you know you have to  know if you are a cpq guy you know what  are the different pricing method  available out of the box so that you  know if you get a scenario like that you  can say okay we can do something this  like this right instead of  saying oh we can go and do  custom development so you don't have to  do custom development because it's all  out of box functionality so that's one  of the reason why i'm telling you  uh all these things and also it's  important uh from a certification point  of view as well so that's pretty much i  wanted to cover uh and i hope you guys  have an amazing saturday adios