good everyone i hope you guys have an  amazing day so what i'll do today i will  explain uh account based contractor  pricing so what happens is that let's  say you know you're a company uh you  know is doing business with you know a  few customers right and out of which two  customers are your  loyal customers right so they often buy  stuff so you wanted to  you know keep them in a price in a  discounted way right instead of say for  instance you wanted to sell  um  you know printers right to a customer  for say 250 bucks but on the other hand  there's another company who's pretty  loyal they buy a lot of stuff from your  company so you wanted to sell the  printers to them for say 200 bucks so  that's how  you know a kind of account based  contract pricing works now it's pretty  simple to set up you know  you know a few clicks here and there a  few small tiny configuration and then  we're good to go so uh the first thing  first you know you need to have the cpg  install right if you don't have it then  you may not be able to you know use this  feature in a very convenient way  uh so  what i'm gonna do i will go to an  account okay so  all right  so i'll go here  um i'll just say account  okay i just got account  so i wanted to pick and choose an  account which is and to make it as a  favorite customer so i can give them the  discount so i'll choose  all accounts  right  and i will say  um  clean manner okay so i'll choose this  one  clan manner account so i will go to uh  on the related in a list there's  something called contact price so i'll  go to content price  so i will add in product  okay  so before  okay before we do that let's look at a  product okay  excuse me  so i will say  video to editor license  i'm not sure if you got a price book for  it  okay we got a price book so we got 200  bucks for  uh video  editor license okay so i will uh since  the this particular customer is a loyal  customer so i'll make this price to say  thousand bucks okay  so  i'll go back to accounts  and i will choose this clean manner  but i apologize if i didn't pronounce  the name correctly so  okay so i got a new this contract price  right got a new  come on  uh  and what i'll do  i will select for the product  and video edits a license okay i'll put  the price here to  a thousand bucks okay  that's pretty much it  that's all you have to do okay now let's  go to code  okay so i'll show you first how this  pricing works when you're using a  separate customer okay i'll go to new  code  okay  and let's start with the new code right  just to make it simple  um  it's taking its own time right i don't  know why whenever i try to use the code  it just like ages  okay  so i'll make it as a primary code  uh i'll choose the accounts okay i'll  choose this one um  this one okay  uh all right i'll choose a different one  right so forget about it i'll choose  all right what's the name of the so  there's something called  uh dickinson palace  uh whatever it is right uh so i'll  choose this  and i will say save  and  okay now we'll go to the code line and  add the product  okay all right  okay edit lines  and  yeah it's gonna take you some time i  told you  for some reason code lines i  sometimes wonder  you know  behind the scene if it's if it's  actually using the right queries right  okay i'll use a standard price book okay  i don't care  um and i will add a product  okay so i had a product  and i'll do the video  whatever i  mediated to license i hope this is the  one  draw on the box okay  and i'll select it okay  i mean this customer is not it's not a  favorite customer so we are charging  them  a normal price right whatever the price  you have in the price book so 200 bucks  pretty simple so this is how i'm gonna  make a code for this customer  fantastic right okay now let's create a  code for uh the other  customer okay so i'll go back so i don't  worry about it so just go back to code  yeah  i'll go to new  and  i will choose account  to this client banner  make it primary  yeah  and i'll do save  okay it's gonna do something all right  so what i'll do i will do edit lines  so  and okay standard price work i honestly  don't care  i will add a product  i will do  video  create the license just to 100 okay just  wait and see  uh i will do select yeah  so you see thousand bucks right this is  how it works because  i have made a contractor price for the  specific account i changed the price a  thousand right now this is a special  customer so i wanted to give this  customer a special price right so this  is how it works pretty bad fantastic oh  feature and pretty simple to do so right  so that's  pretty much i wanted to demonstrate uh i  just want i have one more uh news to  share i mean you might like it so if you  remember i didn't mention that after  this course i will start an experience  cloud which is great now after that i  will do velocity right omni studio the  reason being um i will be working on an  omnistudio project i can't describe much  but i'm just saying i'll be working on  it and once i get an experience i will  go get myself certified so i will  make a video just to give you guys you  know how to go about doing the stuff and  in the process i followed because i  don't like to take certification without  actually working on the stuff i know  that people do that but i'm not the kind  of guy because for me  without real life experience  certification is just pointless right i  mean i need to get their hands on a real  industry experience yeah i do understand  right if you wanted to get into  salesforce getting an admin  certification that's fine perfectly all  right i'm not saying anything wrong with  that but i'm just saying  you know in my case i cannot take  certification without having a real life  experience right at least i need to have  even a tiny bit of implementation  experience  so once i have that you know i'm pretty  happy to get certified right and once i  get certified i'm happy to train you  guys to you know show you how to get  certified using tips and tricks right  and as usual i'll be making the video  series free right  right so that's pretty much i wanted to  cover i hope you guys have an amazing uh  saturday adios