good everyone i hope you guys have an  amazing day so today i'm going to talk  about a manual price override so you  would have seen different pricing  methods right we talked about the list  price we talked about  you know  uh  different ways to set up uh other  pricing methods so sometimes what  happens is all right the business don't  want  uh you know cpg to calculate  uh  the price instead they want this the  sales trip to make amendments to the  price before they apply discounts right  so i will show you  what's happening right now and how to  uh allow a sales rep to you know  make modification to the price okay it's  pretty simple  so you go to the  let me go to the code right  and  and what i'll do i will go to a simple  code  maybe an existing one right so i'll go  to this one with the zero  and i will try to  add a product to the code  let's say  yes it's gonna take some time usually  um  you know you might have seen that uh the  code lines a bit slower for whatever  reason  okay add products  and what i'll do i will go for samsung  uh watch  um and i'll try to add it yeah  so  now  if you notice here right  it says 250 bucks okay because it's  you're letting um cpq to calculate it  based on the  the pricing uh  the pricing method you use right okay  now  i wanted to change the custom unit price  and there's no way as a sales rep i can  do that here right  and this is something i was talking  about a manual override where you know  business wants you know say they wanted  to uh change it to say  270 bucks instead of 250 750 and then  give discount right  just an example  um so under current scenario we can't do  that  so it's pretty simple to achieve it so  for that we go to samsung watch product  so go to product here  and we go to samsung watch  and what we do we will do edit  and we will do  go here  and pricing method editable okay we take  this one  and we'll save it  okay  now we go back to the code  and we go back to the same code right  and we do edit lines  and  what happens is you go to  add product  and i will do samsung  [Music]  watch  and i'll select the samsung watch  and i'll select  and what i'll do i'll go to this  right at  forward direction  pointer and now you can see that the  pricing method is editable okay  but the one thing you notice right  you still can't edit the custom unit  price here that's because  it's still set to list  for that change it to custom right  and i just calculated  and now you see you can edit the unit  price okay now i'll say 270 bucks  and i will calculate okay now you have  to remember one thing if you change the  custom method  say something else let's say block okay  and calculate  very calculated and i'll explain to you  what's happening  okay that's fine  all right no race percentage of total  um i think it's  right now when you change the percentage  of total right  you can't change this custom you know  price which is  which is uh perfectly  uh makes sense right percentage of total  explain to right it doesn't work this  way  so  you go back  and you go to custom  so you do calculate you can change uh  the price you're giving  um  the sales rep and option to manually  overwrite okay so just say 70  calculate  and  i will say save  right  now go to edit lines so  um  you will have  270 bucks uh  worth  of a product in your code okay so this  is how you do a manual override it's a  pretty simple option uh i haven't seen a  lot of businesses uh follow this process  but you know for whatever reason right  if your business decides to  give a sales rep an option to override a  price then this is the way to do it it's  pretty simple right and also you may not  want to give an option to override on  every product right so that's why it's  product specific  so that's pretty much i wanted to cover  it's pretty uh simple explanation i i  believe so in saying so i hope you guys  have an amazing monday adios