good everyone i hope you guys have an  amazing day so in the previous episode i  if you remember i did spoke about how to  sell a product using subscription model  right we talked about a license like  software license if you wanted to sell  um say for three years you can sell it  by subscription right and how to enable  the subscription and subscription terms  right and prorate uh  options right we talked about that  briefly and i hope you enjoyed it so  today you know i'm going to talk about a  scenario and i'm going to talk about  uh multi-dimensional code so why do we  need a multi-dimensional code let's say  i'm selling a software license right  let's say i wanted to sell a vpn license  for three years or two years okay so i  wanted to do uh say uh two percent i  wanted to give two percent discount on  the year one  and on the second year i want to  increase the quantity to two right under  normal coding system we can't really do  that right so to do that we have to  enable  uh you know the concept of  multi-dimensional coding right and  that's the fantastic feature of the cpq  and i can show you with few clicks you  will be able to achieve that target  pretty pretty straightforward okay so  the first thing first i would highly  encourage you guys to register for an  org if you haven't done so i think if  you're preparing for cpq certification  you should have an org ready if you  don't then i'm afraid it's not really  you know  good use of your time just watching  videos because you have to do hands-on  right otherwise you will not retain the  information you will not know what  you're exactly trying to do okay  all right so what i'll do uh i will go  to a simple product okay uh i'll go to  vpn license  excuse me uh and i'll show you a couple  of options  edit  okay  and the first thing first what i'll do  uh i'll show you the subscription term  right so this is a subscription-based  product because we have a fixed price  and we have subscription terms for 12  months  right  and  for now that's uh pretty much  uh  you have to let just a second let me  let's see if you need to change  anything  okay that's pretty much you have to  worry at this stage okay now  how to enable  uh you know multi-dimensional coding  because that can be done on the products  side okay so if you look in the  right-hand side there's something called  price dimension so i've already done  that so you have to create an entry so  it's pretty simple so what do you do you  just go to new okay and if you're  looking at the yearly right you can do  yearly you can do quarterly you can do  monthly  so just give a name and for now because  i'm beating  across the ear right we're talking about  early subscription  um so when you talk about an early  subscription so  uh  ear makes sense okay so just give an ear  give some name that's it okay  uh that's pretty much i'm done i give it  a name called here dimension  all right now go to code  okay  and what i'll do i'll create a new code  okay  um  it's gonna take time it's all right okay  so i'll do  expires on i i just remove the expiry  date i don't care  uh and i'll put the subscription term  for 24 months okay  and i will say  save  okay i'll do the same  okay and now i'll go to  edit lines  right and uh  [Music]  so  idly okay so i'm going to use the  standard price book so normally what  happens right under normal scenario if  you're not dealing with the  multi-dimensional code  so you add a product okay so it will not  give you an option to edit the quantity  for a year year one or edit the quantity  for you two it will not give you an  option uh like split into year one year  two you will see in a second what i mean  by that so if i add product  okay  um  and i will say vpn  and also vpn license  choose this one  okay so you can see you have ear one ear  two right so it's split into two parts  and now  uh if you wanted to see  the the initial view if you're not  talking in terms of multi-dimensional  coding how it would look like so there's  an option here right d segment line so  if i click there so this is what you'd  normally see right uh  something like that  so  you see one quantity one and you know 20  bucks because basically you're you're  buying  for two years and say hey this is a  quantity  uh you know do whatever you want with it  now i wanted to split right i wanted to  give say one percent discount on year  one and i want to increase the quantity  to two for you two right so you can't do  that using this okay if i wanted to try  you can probably increase the quantity  but that will increase the quality for  uh so for instance if i increase it to  say two so what happens is so if i  calculate it  so it will say okay i'll double the  price because it's comparing  uh the 24 months right subscription  terms instead of splitting my earbud  here right so i'll change it back  and  and i go to resegment line  okay  and i'll show you the magic it's it's  fantastic feature i really love this one  okay so i will so you got this forward  looking arrows thinking right so click  here  go to this okay so you can see you can  tweak the things based on here okay so  the first requirement i wanted to give  additional discount so i would say i'm  gonna give one percent okay let this boy  get one percent so and  and then i will increase the quantity to  say two for the second year okay i'm not  giving any discount on the second year  but and i'm gonna do calculate  okay  all right so you can see the discount  applied on the first year nine dollar  ninety cents  and the second year  i'm buying  two licenses so to 20. so it's kind of  split it right so this is the beauty of  it now um that's great now i'll show you  one thing okay so let me cancel this  now what if say for instance  you wanted to  say uh okay let me let me show you what  i mean by that  so just uh just hang on for a second  uh so if i wanted to add the same  product okay so you will see  vpn uh  i said vpn license  excuse me  i still got a runny nose so it's bloody  the weather change but anyways so you  can see that you're getting body falls  uh  uh you know the the segmented options  right i don't want this  options to be shown so for instance if  i'm a customer i said i do understand  that we're dealing with the multi-code  but i don't want to see this view i want  whenever you add a product i wanted to  see something like this instead of  seeing this way  is it possible  absolutely so  it's pretty simple so you go back to the  product  okay  and go vpn license  and we'll choose edit  um excuse me and then you go to this  default pricing table  so change it to  uh sorry standard  okay  so  when that happens right you say okay  show the default view as the  as non-segmented one okay so i'm gonna  save  um i will  refresh this page  and go to the code  okay i'm gonna use the same code right  um  edit the lines  okay  all right add product  uh and i'll say vpn  okay  and i'll save vp license i see the magic  you see you're not getting the the multi  code coder view right you can if you  want it you can go to the resegment line  but by default right you won't get this  option when you add a product to the  code right so this is exactly what i  wanted to demonstrate today i hope you  enjoyed it it's a powerful feature  though uh i've seen people using this  option i've seen people not using it and  i wanted to turn it off for whatever  reason so this is really a fantastic  option i mean if you  uh get a chance to read about it i would  highly encourage you to go to trailhead  and read about it i really love this  feature right so  in saying so that's pretty much i wanted  to talk about in today's episode i hope  you guys have an amazing day adios