good everyone i hope you guys have an  amazing day um so in the last episode i  talked about multi-dimensional code uh  so in this episode i'll be talking  more on the lines right we're gonna look  at different options and to see what  that means right from a  multi-dimensional code perspective okay  so  if you remember uh if you recall the  last episode right what i've done i  created a code right and i've created a  product and enable the multi-dimensional  coding option right  so if you go to this product here  um go to vpn license this is the one  which i've used right and all i've done  was that i've better the price  dimensions okay now the price dimensions  is pretty cool right so it lets you add  you know the price dimension a record  and with the type right so in today's  episode i will focus more on the type  and i'll tell you why okay so i just  wanted to run through one scenario then  we come back to the type because if i go  back to the code excuse me and i choose  this code right  so normally what happens is right i'm  going to choose a code uh  say instead of 24 month subscription  right i will choose a 16 month  subscription that means  you will have um you know 12 months in a  year  and then you know four months in the  next year right i hope that makes sense  so what i've done  um in this specific code  um i just specified the start date right  just to make it simple  so what i've said the code start from  the first of january 2022 okay  so i'm going to add product  and  i'll just go for vpn license  i'll use the same  and select  so  you're not seeing the segmented one here  because if you remember i'm  enabled  uh  in a product  to not to by default not to  show  uh segmented display so i can do that  here by  resegment  okay now  uh what i've done so you know i've added  a product  uh so now it will segment into two years  right so if you  expand this one  uh you can see that you start from first  off uh january 2022  and end date so as 12  the christmas sorry not christmas uh so  the end of the year right the december  and then it will start for the the next  year from the first of jan  and it will end on uh april right so  pretty simple okay  now you might  so  you might look at this and you might say  hey i don't have an end date for  whatever reason right if if you're not  able to see end date so you can add that  it's pretty simple i'll just show you in  a second how to do that  so so what i'm trying to  show you here right so if you wanted to  um you know segment your  uh the code right in like in a  multi-dimensional way you can do that  but now that's a sales rep right say you  might get a requirement where they say  hey i don't want the first year  uh from the first of um  uh say first of uh jan 2022 till uh  december 2022 what i want to do is that  i want this first year to be  from the 1st of jan 2022 till  the 31st of may 2022 and the remaining  should go under year two is that  possible absolutely it's possible so if  you remember uh when i started this uh  lecture i talked about type right and i  said we're gonna revisit that so that's  exactly what we're gonna do okay so  before i talk about type right uh i was  i was mentioning uh about end date right  and you might say hey i can't see end  date so to get that option all you have  to do go to the setup okay  and we will go to the setup here  and  go to the object manager  right  and  code  lines  okay  and a field set  um so you just go to this uh segment  line editor  okay  so if you don't see the end date here  just drag from this  down right that's all you have to do  okay in case if you're after this option  if you for for whatever reason if you  can't see this  because the reason why i'm telling this  you know i remember this experience when  someone saying hey i can't see an ending  can you show me how to do that so this  is how you do it right okay all right  sweet now go back to the code okay so  now we wanted to change this right now i  will not save this code i will just  cancel it  now i'll go back to the product again  okay  now i'll go back to the same product vpn  license and i'll go back to the price  dimensions  okay and i wanted to edit this yearly  dimensions so i'm gonna do edit  now the main intention you should be  focusing on type because you know in the  previous episode i configured this to be  as an ear to which means that you know  the it will segment based on or  segregate based on ear okay which is  cool but that's not the requirement  right the requirement is i wanted to  uh segregate based on you know my own  requirement like i wanted you know first  year from say jan  to may okay and the second year from you  know whatever from that  so can you do that that's the question  and the answer to that is absolutely so  all you have to do uh change the type  from here to custom okay that's all you  have to do  and you save  right now let's go back to the code let  me refresh this you know  um  and we will  go to the same code okay  and i will choose the edit lines and add  that  product here  add product  so i will say vpn  uh chooses  right now see the difference okay now  this is not the segregated view so i  just wanted to  now you see the custom here right  so this is what  enables a sales rep or an agent to  configure this based on on the custom  requirement so our requirement is we  want from uh  um  first of uh  jan to 31st of may right in the in in  the first section and in the second they  were  from uh first of june  to whatever  so i'll go here okay  so  remember this date okay  and i change the name from here to i'll  say first year  and i will say plus  and i'll say second year  okay so the requirement is okay i'll  copy this because this is the last year  so the requirement is i want the first  day  from the first off the first year should  be from the 1st of jan 2022 till um  31st of  2022  may  30th 31st okay  and obviously the second year should  start from  um  where is it  chewing right  looks all right to me  okay i'll save it  um it's gonna take a few while okay  that's saved now you can see the first  year and second year let's see the  difference  the start date is from first of jan and  end eighties from uh and that is the  31st of may um and the the second year  star from you know whatever  so this is how you can customize it  right if you wanted to specify custom  date you can do that it's pretty  powerful option now i just wanted to  mention one more thing  let's say you wanted to  um  uh custom from  um instead of the 6th of june right you  wonder the second uh  segment should start from say  uh first of july okay  now can you do that let's find out  okay so you got this message the start  date of each segment must be the day  after the previous segment so basically  it's complaining that okay you cannot do  that  but  we have a configuration using which you  can achieve this okay so i will cancel  this okay  and i will go back to this the second  page i go to setup okay  and i will say install  okay go to the install package  go to configure  right  and go to the pricing and calculation  and there is this option allow  non-consecutive custom segments so i  just take it  save it  okay and uh  let me refresh it okay this one  all right so we'll say i product  and i will say vpn  vpn license and select  um  all right you just  re-segment it  custom right as you usually remember  this one  so just say first year  right  and i'll say  second year  and  so  this one  is still may right  that's requirement  and this one we said we want it from  um july right so first of july let's see  if it works or not right  all right didn't complain so  obviously that seems to work  okay so  this is how it works right as you can  see that he wanted to start the second  year from uh  um you know a month later so you can do  that using that configuration it's  pretty powerful option right  sometimes you might realize hey that's  not working so this is one of the  options you have to  take but in most scenario right the  customer may not want that but it  depends upon the business context right  what you're trying to achieve because  everything is driven by a business  requirement right  at the end of the day cpq is just a tool  right and we are here to solve the  problem for a customer so they have a  business need and you're trying to use  the sales force to to solve that  business uh problem right so  uh that's the one thing you should  always remember right tool is just tool  right you can use omnistudio you can use  salesforce you can use aws you can use  you know other technology it doesn't  matter right these are just the tool  right at the end of the day so  uh you you the main goal is to solve a  customer problem right um so that's okay  anyway sorry digress okay now one more  option i wanted to talk about before uh  i close this episode for today uh so  there if you remember  um there if you if uh  i mentioned about the type right where  i've changed the type to  say you know the custom  now  if there is another type  uh which i wanted to talk about that is  the the runtime okay so now the one time  except for instance right um you were  you  so you bought a computer okay  so now  you are pretty new to you know how to  use computer and you don't know anything  about how to assemble it so you asked  someone to come and you know assemble it  for you okay you know install the  software and do whatever right so they  say we wanted to charge 50 bucks for it  it's like a one-off fee okay and there  is no discount  applicable to that whatsoever  so how do you achieve that so to achieve  that you use this option called one  timer i mean just a scenario this is a  one specific scenario you might have  different a reason why you should be  doing just one of payment right or uh  you're joining a group right so you have  to do so or so for okay or or another  option i can give you uh you're joining  a gym right  you're joining a like like for instance  in new zealand we have a gym called city  fitness right pretty fantastic gym uh  i've been a member for  three years right so when you join a gym  for the first time right you have to ask  you have to pay a one-off fee right you  know just that's for to making your  access card and that kind of stuff so  that one of fee right you can call it as  a one-time fee okay like 50 bucks or 60  bucks or whatever so the same thing what  we're gonna do uh for this vpn license  let's say um you're pretty new you don't  know how to you know configure it so you  are getting a 20 one off phone support  to configure it so it's let's say you  know 30 bucks for it right pretty sweet  so to do that you have to create a new  record so you're just going to say new  say  initial  installation  installation fee right  i'm just going to do one off and here  you have to  say okay i wanted to  charge them 30 bucks  obviously labor is expensive so  and now  so non-discountable  so do you want to make it as a  non-discountable which means that do you  you wanted to uh  allow  sales rep not to give discount so yeah  so you can say yeah  okay now i'm gonna go to the code  um  excuse me and i will go to the same code  and  edit lines  um  a product  and what is this about vpn  choose this  select  um all right just a second let's go back  here  there you go  installation fee  um and if you go down  and you see that this is 30 bucks what  we charge  and you got um the one of you for it  right so this is how you normally do it  if you wanted to give a one-off you know  if you wanted to charge a one-off fee  right in this case insulation um fees  right uh so and the custom as you can  see right you can configure you know the  custom date which i've already explained  to you before so this is uh what i  wanted to cover in today's episode i  hope you enjoyed it this is pretty  important right from exam point of view  also from a you know  from a normal implementation perspective  so  yeah so that's being said i hope you  guys have an amazing saturday adios