good everyone i hope you guys have an  amazing day um so if you remember in the  last episode i talked about the volume  based discount right which is pretty  simple  right you keep this going based on the  volume um so you if you remember i did  talk about how to configure the discount  schedule  the for instance i configure this the  discount options  and  i provided  two tiers right  like three items in a bow  uh you'll give 10 discount 10 and about  gives 15 discount  what if right a company has a  requirement where they don't want to  give volume based discount based on the  discount percent  instead they want to give based on an  amount for instance  um they wanted to give  so uh you know  uh from three to you know 10 upper bound  instead of 10  they want to give 10  discount  right  um and from 10 to 20 they wanted to give  say a 15 discount instead of 15  i mean this might be a scenario in  certain  companies that might  have uh you know certain fixed amount of  discount uh for a product so they may  not want to keep the percentage based  instead they wanted to give uh amount  based discount so how to do that it's  pretty simple so what i'll do i'll go  back to the discount schedule right and  i'll open this discount options here  and if you see that  under this you have something called  discount unit  uh change this to  from percent to amount  right and then you save it now when you  save this right you will see  a difference when you go and try  to edit the tiers  that is  you see that the discount  sign change to the discount dollar sign  so what are you trying to say here is  that hey  from uh  three  about  and till ten i'll be paying you know i'm  keen to uh pay 10 discount  uh instead of paying you know uh 10  discount so  uh the prices got changed  to  from a percentage to the amount  okay so that's all you have to do in  this case and let's see how it works uh  when i try to create a code  okay so i'll go to the same code which i  did last time and i'll go to edit lines  um  and i'll go to  um  i think this was the 10 something  yeah the 10 inch tablet  so i'll do there right and i'll do  select okay  all right so if you look at it the  discount will kick in right because i'm  only i'm  so because i'm only selling uh quantity  value  as one  so what i'll do i'll change it to four  um because the match gets easier right  when you have  uh the even numbers  excuse me  all right so i got  um  560 okay  um so because  um it calculated  uh based on  uh you know the the ten dollar  calculation based on that right  um so  uh  so what it did it did ten dollar for uh  four products so let's see i will change  it to a six okay  so  all right so what happens is so six  times 150 is  [Music]  900 and we said hey i wanted to give 10  discount on each product right each  quantity so it subtracted  10 times 6 which is 60. so  900 minus 60 is  840 right so that's how it works it's  it's pretty clear right okay now um what  if  i don't want to give a discount on  entire product  i'm sorry entire quantity say  um what if uh like for instance i have  six products here right and if you if i  go back to the discount schedule if you  remember i said three and a bow what if  i i wanted to keep discount only from  three and above right  uh i don't want to give discounts so i  wanted to get discount uh only on the  four  extra quantities here instead of  including six right  because obviously you're saying that if  you buy more than three products you'll  be eligible for discount but i only  wanted to keep discount only for  uh from the eligibility uh mark right  from means two and a three in about so  that means if you are buying six right  so you should be eligible  for four products  to be  uh categorized under discount  uh option and the two you should be  excluding it so that might seems like a  bit complex requirement right if you  saying hey how do i split two out of it  and only give discounts to the four  products that sounds difficult no not  really because we have an outer box  option which is pretty pretty  straightforward so what i'll do i'll go  to the discount schedule here  uh and i'll go to discount options  so  you see the range right so we have  something on range  so  range pretty much applies to the entire  product  uh quantity and so instead i'll use  something called slab  so what slab will do  right it will  start calculating discount  from the threshold  okay  so  at the chairs  so  it is saying okay i just wanted to give  the discount  uh from  um okay so wait a second  i will change it to the  percent just to make it easier  okay this is cool right  so it's back to percentage so  the slab  the functionality of slab is right it  will say hey uh out of six quantities  right i'm only going to give you this  count for four quantities because it's a  slab right this counts will only kick in  uh  from the minimum threshold value that's  from three okay  so what i'll do i'll go to code  and explain to you the calculation is  pretty simple  sorry not new code i'm not interested to  create it  it can get a little bit confusing that  especially the calculations behind the  scene but  it's not too hard guys it's just you  know you just need to understand  what the software is doing behind the  scene that's all  okay so i'm gonna do add products  and i will say 10  yeah and  just here  um select  okay so what i'll do  i will do  um  six right  let's do four first okay  so  four okay  now how this is going to work okay i'll  i'll show you let me calculate it first  right  so  it is  working on  uh  the last  two quantities  uh instead of um  so  it is giving um  okay  um  wait a second  let me use a calculator and explain to  you guys how it works right  it will make it clear okay so what we  have we have 150  times  four right  that's normally supposed to be  uh the total value of this uh product  with the quantity of four  right now  um  here we can see that we're getting 30  off okay now you must be thinking where  am i getting that from okay now if you  remember the slab right slab comes into  picture  uh when the threshold hits so we have  four products okay so the so it will  exclude the first two right so it's a  hey i don't care just bugger up with the  for the first two right so the first two  is gone so now we're left with only two  right  so  two  times 150  okay ah crap  2 times 150  that's 300 okay now  what slab tells you right i'm gonna give  this count on this value okay that's a  ten percent  um  of the three uh thirty three hundred  that is the thirty bucks so that's why  you're getting 570. okay let's do one  more example just to make it more clear  i'm gonna do six okay  um quick save  sorry not quick set  okay 8 40. now you must be thinking  okay how's that's going to happen or how  is that working all right okay so what  we'll do we're just gonna open the  calculator  um so  we have um what's that six times  150  that's 900  and we're getting 60 bucks as a discount  right  all right so  since we are using slab right so what  the slab will say  i'm going to exclude the first two  because we're saying the threshold  starts at the  third position right so basically  it will ignore the first two  quantity so we so that means we have  four quantities in the hand so the  discount will be applied  uh to those four quantities so the four  quantities means we got four times  150  and 600 and the 10  obviously 60. so that's how we're  getting 840 right  so this is  a pretty interesting concept but um  uh once you understand it it's very easy  to use guys i mean some of the companies  will say hey i want this options i  wanted to do this  so you need to know how to do these are  out of box functionality it's not you  don't have to do any sort of  customization to get this  uh you know get this  kind of  solution so it's all out of box cpg  functionality so you should know how to  use it so once you know  you're good to go so that's being said  that's all i wanted to talk about in  this episode i hope you guys have an  amazing uh tuesday adios