good everyone I hope you guys have an  amazing day  um so in this episode what I'm going to  do I will talk about conditional uh  rendering uh of of a layout uh in a code  document  so what that means is that let's say  um you wanted to send out a code  document  um to uh to XYZ company so you will have  you might have specified uh a code  template right and you wanted to use the  same template but now uh what happens is  that under certain scenario you don't  want to send out certain section from  the template to every customer say you  might have you know specific header uh  you don't want to send out you know to a  specific customer and you want to send  out the specific header to a specific  customer right so in that case you know  you have a pretty a pretty uh decent  option to create uh different code  template but I mean it might work if you  have you know few of them right like  three four code templates but if imagine  uh if you have like you know 50  customers uh with the different uh tiny  bit of change and then you want to  conditionally hide certain section from  a template so it kind of makes it uh  looks ugly right from an admin  perspective you have to create multiple  code templates just to cater for a  couple of scenarios so keeping that into  consideration the cpq there is something  called conditional rendering so which is  pretty simple to implement it so you can  Implement in in pretty different ways so  the way I implement it is pretty much a  trailer example so I've created a field  first of all  you need to log into org if you haven't  done so so so we got something called  code right  uh so the code I create a field so you  can do different ways you can uh you  know hide different section space and  different things  um so in code  uh I've created something called  um I think it's conditional  uh let me see  just a second I'm out of the field  um  account just let me go to code first let  me find out  okay  um  okay sorry uh it's called Uh include  color page  so what I'm saying that I won't include  a cover page right so I've added that a  checkbox it's like a basic thing right  uh then I  added that specific checkbox API name to  uh to the value of a pick list so so  what I did so first thing right I've  created a  a checkbox right and the code template  as I've already demonstrated then you go  to something called template section  [Music]  um  object and then under template section  you go to field the relationship  and then you look for conditional print  field right so you open that  so when you open that uh under the value  you just need to add the API name of the  field you've created  that's pretty much you have to do yeah  okay now after that what I've done right  I've created a a new  uh template section  foreign  content which comes in the template  content which is pretty much a basic  HDMI which is HTML file  which is the  you know ugly looking HTML file  which contains some merge Fields right  okay so after that uh if you've been  following along uh in my previous  episode I've demonstrated how to  customize your code template right using  a section so you create a code template  then you go to this related list and  under sections you add different stuff  right so I have done pretty much similar  for this one as well so as you can see  that I've created this uh Templar  content detail which is an HTML file  right so I'll go to  Second code template  so this is the one we have as you can  see that I'm now creating a new one I'm  going to make use of an existing one so  I go to new template and then under  related tab  uh I have added a cover page with the  display address one so if I look at it  the only difference I've done I've added  the top margin to one so if I go edit  yeah so I said okay the section name  which is the name of your section that's  a cover page margin I've added and the  print conditional field right this is  important so this is what you're going  to tell  um  uh your  cpq that okay so if you use this field  right uh then only this particular cover  page will be printed okay this is pretty  cool so you can add other fields right  wherever you wanted to print  okay so that's done so let's go to code  yeah and I'll pick a basic code so I'll  pick this one yeah  uh and I will say uh General document  and I'll choose the new template right  and I will say preview  all right so now you must be wondering  okay we talked about printing that fancy  looking HTML page where is it or where  is that section  uh well the section won't print in this  case because you haven't turned on the  switch yet so when I talk about the  switch it's a checkbox  so you go to this call right and in the  code  so what I'll do I will  take this option include color page  and I'll save it okay and then I will  say generate document  and I will say template yeah  and I'll say preview  there you go so you can see that it's  printed right now it's it's kind of  fatty looking  um  code document so this is how you can  conditionally render certain section uh  if you are interested if that's what  your business requirement because  usually like I said right what might  happen your business might say hey I  don't want to print this for certain  customers I wanted to print this for  certain customers so instead of creating  you know multiple uh you know the code  templates you can pretty much use the  same template and use section to play  with it which is pretty simple right  because think about this way right if  you have done programming before our  main intention is to make use of  existing functionality right rather than  Reinventing Your wheel so that's pretty  much what we've done here so in saying  so that's pretty much I wanted to cover  so I hope you guys have an amazing uh  Thursday adios