good everyone I hope you guys have an  amazing day so in this episode what I'm  gonna do I'll talk about uh something  called code terms so so far we have seen  how to create a template and adding  sections to it uh so sometimes you know  not sometimes most of the times right  when you send out a proposal to a  customer you often add your terms and  conditions right uh regarding what  happens you know when you don't get  product on time and regarding the return  policy such you know different things so  what I'm going to do I'll show you how  to add a uh the terms and condition or  the code terms to your code template  that's pretty much we're going to cover  that's because after that that will  pretty much marks the end of our code  templation okay so the first thing first  right you need to log into your work if  you don't have one it's the right time  to get one  it's uh so you go to the Tic Tac toggle  icon and I'll look for something called  template content  um and what I'll do  I will say  okay so there's something called code  terms  so I'll select that and I will say you  know  terms  right  and also 10  for cigarette  okay  uh so that's you know so I've created  this uh the section right which is  pretty cool now what I'll do I will go  to something called  um core terms right  and on the code terms we got lots of  terms existing one right so we can make  use of an existing one that's fine uh I  don't think there is anything wrong with  that but in saying so uh what I'll do I  will  um  use  create a new one so I'll say print order  just  I'll just say 40 whatever right  uh so you just search for the code terms  so you know you can search the parent  code terms so you know if you wanted to  link the pairing code tell me you can do  that and I'm just not bothered with that  I would say this is we have a zero  refund policy  in in terms of  damage caused by customer  um  yeah  yeah  um  okay  something like that you can do that  right so I've created this this is  pretty cool now what I'll do I will go  to the code template if you remember we  talked about the code template right so  we created this code template and I've  added different section to it so I will  go to the there's one thing  um before we do that  um there is a something called  terms  so number terms right just put a tick to  this so this will say uh if the code  terms rendered by this template should  be numbered okay so if you wanted to to  to have this numbered so put that thick  option  okay now what I'll do I'll go to the  related list and if you remember we've  been adding uh different stuff to the  sections uh as we are customizing our  code document right so we had a cover  page we had a header uh we had a line  items now we will do  add the code items uh terms so the terms  uh top marginals at 0.3  uh content I will say terms  um and  display order I would say four yeah  and I'll save it  yeah let's try to print it and let's see  what happens  uh generate document  thank you  I select the template  and I'll preview it  I don't know if you've been following  along for a whole this time You Must Be  Wondering ah this is really so you see  that  um we got this  um  the extra you know the  the terms and condition that came apart  came over here  but you must be thinking Hmm  why the heck all of this came from right  why are we getting this one okay  all right we can sell that one so what  I'll do I will go to the code term  and I will look at all the terms  and so apparently it seems like this is  the one  um that is getting hit right that's  getting  [Music]  um  so it's got locked and it's called the  parent term  and let's say the print order okay now  this is getting printed because it has a  print order 20 right so what I'll do I  will actually go to the the one which  I've created  maybe this one  so if you look at it right so this is  not working because of the print order  what we have right so what I'll do I  will go to the this one and I will say  hey make this print order to say eight  and I'll say code  and it's going to take me some time  all right let's see what happens  oh yeah it's still printing the okay we  have  zero refund policy  if the terms of the damage caused by  customer negligence you see we got this  printed all right so this one got  printed at the top now before what was  happening was that because because of  the print orders right we have in place  it was printing in a different way in a  different order so I moved it to eight  so it's printing but let's say I don't  want it to print any of this stuff  right so it's it's pretty simple what  you can do so see these are the  different terms that's getting printed  like you see you have different terms uh  you have different terms all these code  terms right as long as you have uh  active code terms it get printed so  let's say I only wanted to print this  one for now right I'll show you in the  next episode uh you know how to  conditionally stop it but for now uh if  you don't want to print it uh just for  time being you know what I'll show you  uh how to  uh you can pretty much  um  say  you can say I don't want this  so you can untick it you can say untick  it and take into I I don't want any of  this on active I don't want any of this  active  I don't want any of this actually I only  want this to be acting right  okay so right now we got only one active  okay so when you go to the codes and try  to print it again  uh this is not a great option though I'm  just telling you but I'll show you in  the next episode how to conditionally  you know print different terms  okay  you want to see we got only one printed  so that's  pretty much I wanted to cover in in  today's episode right so that being said  I hope you guys have an amazing Tuesday  videos