good everyone I hope you guys have an  amazing day so in the last episode I uh  talked about creating  um a multiple orders from a single code  uh which is great but the only thing you  remember I have to do a manual step  where I have to go and create an order  myself and split it right now how about  we can automate those process right it  would be very awesome right if you don't  really have to go and manually create a  code instead sorry manually create an  order instead uh you know based on the  the code of items line items your code  can be uh split into uh different orders  right  um there are two ways you can do that  um and we need to do a tiny uh change to  the to the field in the code object so  what I'll do okay  um so I've already done that but I'll  show you anyway so if I go to  um  sorry edit object yeah  so this is obviously  um  code object  uh  so I go to the field relationship right  now what I'll do I'll do order by so  it's a pic oh sorry  order by it's a piclish field so what  I've done I've added a new value  which is that product family right so  what we'll do so the scenario is pretty  simple it's a trailer example right you  can add other field that's fine so I  wanted to filter  based on a product family and then the  product family is different that  quantity will be added to a separate  order so let me give you a very simple  example let's say I have a code item  because I have a code right and in that  code I got like three items right and  two items belong to side product family  Hardware okay and the last item belongs  to a family called software so in this  scenario we will have two orders that's  gonna get created because uh Hardware  will be categorized as one category  um and the  software will be categorized as another  category so we will have two orders  getting generated it's a pretty pretty  simple scenario but some of the  businesses they do go using this route  rather than you know you go on tinkering  with the code and just trying to create  it so I think this approach Works  um other approach you can do group by so  for instance uh in a code you have  multiple groups right so if you have say  you know code belonging to say two  different groups and your line items for  instance I have a code right in that  code I have four items right and say two  items belong to a group a and the last  two items belongs to Group B okay so  what will happen if you try to create a  code behind the scene it will create  sorry try to create an order behind the  scene it will create two orders in zero  one I'll show you how it works uh so  let's go to the the cpg again  um  so  I will go to opportunities  I have this cell separate entries right  and up this code  so and I have this edit line okay  um  and I got these two items each belonging  to a different product  so  when I try to create an order behind the  scene it will create two orders okay  so what I'll do I'll go back to  because I'll save it  and I'll do edit  yeah  and I'll scroll down and  I'll do order yeah and I'll do order by  product family yeah  and I'll save  okay so that got saved  all right now what happens  uh we go to the school account yeah  and it might take a while to create an  order because it's doing behind the  scene  um and I'll go to relate to list  and let's look at the orders okay we got  five  okay so I think these two  other one so let's see this one okay  so this is the admin hour which is a  separate one right  and this is should be the Samsung one  yeah that's the Samsung Note okay so if  you have to cross check just look at the  order  from a code  so just go to excuse me edit lines  as you can see that we got two separate  uh orders  uh created from  um this single code right so what I'll  do I'll try to create another  opportunity right and let's work out a  different scenario  um I'll just put some garbage you know  testing  oh right whatever  I mean in obviously in the real life  scenario you will not put this kind of  name I mean it makes no sense but  for testing I honestly don't care at  this stage so well that's fine  all right I'm gonna create a  um code  new code  from this opportunity  um I'll make this as primary  I'll link this uh testing code and I'll  link the school account  um yeah okay that's pretty cool  um what I'll do I will do edit lines  and I will  I'll choose a price book I don't care  about the price book here I'll do add  group  and or add one I I wanted to add two  groups one I'll say  uh first  and I will set a second yeah  and also add product and I will add a  couple of them let's say I wanted to add  USB key to the first group  and in this one I will add maybe say a  couple of them  Action Insurance in this one  okay  and so what happens is I created a code  right uh with two groups first and  second the first group belongs to this  and this USB key belongs to the first  group that's a product  uh and uh these two products belong to  the second group yeah and I'll save it  okay  all right now  so what I'll do I'll edit this code  right  there is an option uh if you're doing a  group based separation  that is  order by codeline group so you just take  this  and you order this  um  and you'll do this  okay so orders are getting generated  behind the scene now let's go back to  the same account  we go to this school account  uh Let me refresh the screen  um go to related one  right okay all right seems like we've  got more orders here  so you see  um  we got these two orders got generator  right so let's look at this one  um this is a two factor which belongs to  the first group yeah  and obviously this one  contains two of them right which belongs  to the other group  so  yeah that's pretty much I wanted to  cover in this episode as you can see I  don't have to manually create an order  right I just have to configure a few  things  um and that's pretty much I have to do  so based on that you're pretty good to  go so I I personally believe right  um  you know some companies use this  approach some companies may not it  depends on your business process what  you know they have in place at the end  of the day it's all driven by business  process right when you are implementing  a solution for a customer  they will have business process in place  if it's a big company or a big Urban  agencies or whatever  um so yeah that being said I hope you  guys have an amazing Wednesday adios