good everyone I hope you guys have an  amazing day so today what I'm going to  do I'll be doing a very tiny uh lecture  today uh so around the advanced approval  process so in the last episode I've  demonstrated how you can set up  um Advanced cpq approval uh and remember  uh before I finished a lot of episode I  uh was I did mention that you know in  the future episode I will show you how  uh submit for approval works right so  that's exactly what I'm going to look at  it today right  um  so  what I'll do I'll go back to the same  code right so I'll just go to the  Salesforce  um cpq  um  I'll go to code  yeah  um and then I'll pick up the same color  right so if you remember  uh last time  um you know I've created this code I've  set up the the approval rules behind the  scene and approval conditions right so  when I create a code and which matches  the uh the criteria so obviously you're  going to trigger an approval process  right so the way I looked at it just go  to the preview approval and once you do  that  um  it will show you a person uh who's  supposed to prove this code right so  this is the Dave Miller okay now what  I'll do I'll what I've done I I clicked  on something for approval okay so when I  did that so we got the Sentry here let  me call approval and this is the record  so it says hey this this is the person  who's supposed to be through it so you  know you can reject the result let's say  you know I'll do this  yeah  okay  so I would say approved yeah  fantastic all right so I'll just do  approved  okay so and we can go here  and you can see that um email and it's a  comments approve right and this the  status has been approved the similarly  uh you know if you decide oh there's a  there's a problem with the code so you  can go and you know  try to do that but not existing all  right I mean I'm just trying to say but  if if you want to reject that existing  one right you'll get this message right  just wanted to be uh careful and but I  thought anyway I'll demonstrate what it  looks like some people will say hey let  me go and try to reject the existing  code which has already been approved  people do silly things right but I mean  I I don't say actually right my  apologies I didn't mean to use the words  today I mean people try to see if that  works right I mean I really consider  that's a good start because that means  they are testing the software so so my  apologies I didn't really mean to you  socially okay so what I'll do  um so let me create a remote code right  so I'll show you remember that  um let me look at this code to see  if this matches the requirement  okay so we have already one more code in  place so this uh needs approval as well  yeah so what I'll do right now uh as you  can see uh this approval uh entry is  empty because we haven't submitted this  for approval so I'll do click or  something for approval  um so it's just doing behind the scene  uh stuff is supposed to do so for some  reason it then all right let me see if  it did or not  okay so it did right approval so we got  an entry there so just that I need to  refresh it but that's all good so this  time what I'll do I'll try to uh reject  it okay  and I will say hey the code  has some problem  please correct it right  okay  and  right so  and as you can see that  um to go to approval here  and the code is being rejected  yeah  so yeah that's that's how the approval  and uh rejection process works it's  pretty simple  um if you have done approval process in  Salesforce you will know this is pretty  much the same stuff it's except that  it's it has more capability right so and  it's and it's pretty cool right to use  the cpq bands approval for the cpq stuff  so that's pretty much I I wanted to  cover in this episode so that being said  I hope you guys have an amazing Saturday  adios